



☑ nick@nickbarth.ca

L+1 (780) 932 4869

★ 108 Dorchester Drive, St. Albert, Alberta, Canada T8N 4Y4

Summary

I am a senior designer and developer specializing in web and mobile technologies. As a full stack developer I've lead development projects and successfully executed on design and marketing strategies increasing revenue and readership, and created both mobile and web apps targeting a wide range of platforms and industries.

Jualifications



Recent History

Mobile / Web Developer, Freelance

(June 2015 - Current), Edmonton, AB

As a developer / designer I've worked on a variety of web and mobile develoment projects ranging from custom Django and Wordpress projects to native and hybrid android and iOS apps for local agencies around the city. These projects utilized a variety of languages and frameworks including Python, PHP, JavaScript, React, NodeJs, Java, and Swift, and also required project management and ui/ux design.

Mobile / Web Developer, Beep Mobile Inc

(June 2013 - June 2015), Edmonton, AB

As a lead member a of the design and development team, I was responsible for mobile iOS, Android, and web based design and development. I was also able to take a leading role in developing web and social media campaigns successfully resulting in the aquisition of hundreds of thousands of new users.

Programmer Analyst III, Servus Credit Union

(June 2012 - June 2013), Edmonton, AB

As a member of The Village intranet initiative, I was able to act as a leading member on the design and user interface team. My responsibilities included front end developement with SharePoint and Web Service APIs, and Web Part design and development, while ensuring consistant corporate branding and identity throughout the application.

.NET Technical Consultant, GE Intelligent Platforms

(Feb 2012 - June 2012), Edmonton, AB

Serving on the UI/UX team for the Mayne MVC.NET project, I was actively involved in designing and developing a real time application used to remotely manage external PLC hardware. My team was responsible for designing a user interface and developing a scalable and secure API consumable by clientside Javascript.

Senior Designer, Saputo Dairy Land

Technical Skills

Server Software:

IIS, SharePoint 2007/2010, Apache, Nginx, APC, Tomcat

Languages:

Microsoft SQL, Oracle, C#, Ruby, Node, Python, Java, PHP, VB .NET, C++, Javascript, CSS3, HTML5

Project Management Tools:

Basecamp, SVN, GIT, Mercurial, Team Foundation Server

Databases:

Oracle, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL, SQLite3, LINQ, Mongo, Redis, Memcached

Hardware:

Dedicated Servers, Windows Azure, Amazon Cloud, Rackspace Cloud

Applications Software:

Team Foundation Server, Power Shell, Bash, Visual Studio .NET, MS Office, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

Industries:

Web, Database, Mobile, Server Administration for Banking, Manufacturing, and Media

Operating Systems:

Windows Server 2008/2010, Red Hat Enterprise, Debian, Ubuntu, Fedora Core, OSX

Methodologies:

Agile Development, Test Driven Development, Kanban, Scrum, Waterfall

Formal Education

Grant Macewan University, 2008

BSc, Computing Science Specialization

Northern Alberta Institute of Technology, 2004

CST, Web Technologies Specialization

References

Available on Request

(Nov 2011 - Feb 2012), Edmonton, AB

Working with an international team of developers across Canada and the United States, I was able to work on and develop for a variety of high profile projects including internal point of sales software, ordering systems, and public facing marketing campaign sites. My responsibilities included database design and modeling, frontend design, and full stack development.